Nicholas Russo

1-925-699-1715 | nijaru0x@gmail.com | https://nijaru.com

SUMMARY

I'm a self-taught software developer with two and a half years of professional experience. I have a breadth of knowledge covering python, go, linux, and building APIs. I'm a strong learner who focuses on writing clean and correct code. I am interested in linux, APIs, AI, networking, and distributed systems.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Omnitier, Inc.

January 2021 - May 2023

- Worked on software for tertiary DNA analysis.
- Primarily built a public python API for our Go and gRPC backend.
- Added small features and bug fixes to our React frontend.
- Built a regression testing system on top of the python API.
- Improved the runtime of one of our python scripts from 45+ minutes to about 5 minutes. I made a minor change that heavily reduced the number of system calls while traversing the filesystem.

IT Support Intern

Robert Half

June 2011 - December 2011

Performed installations of workstations and software. Repaired laptops and desktops.

IT Intern

City of Pleasanton

January 2010 - May 2010

Performed routine IT work. Assisted in a thin client deployment to the city's library.

AWARDS

Money 20/20 Las Vegas Kairos

Kairos - 2nd Place Winner

October 2016

Built a cross-terminal payment application and API for partnering businesses together. I built a Go/PostgreSQL API and deployed it using docker on CoreOS Container Linux.

EDUCATION

Las Positas College, Livermore, CA — Computer Science 2014 - 2015, 2016 - 2018

Computer Science Club President 2016 - 2017

42 Silicon Valley, Fremont, CA — Computer Science 2018 - 2020

Dev Bootcamp, San Francisco, CA — Web Development Fall 2016 - Spring 2017

Chabot College, Hayward, CA — Music Recording Technology 2013-2014

SKILLS

Python

• Ruby/Rails

SQL

Ubuntu/Redhat

• Go

FastAPI/Django

Git/Bash/zsh

Docker/CoreOS

• C/C++

Javascript

AWS/GCP

• Gentoo